上集回顾
Previously...
我的丈夫
My husband.
无论你做什么
Nothing you could ever do
都阻挡不了我对你的爱
could stop my loving you.
乔纳森
Jonathan,
乔纳森 韦克菲尔德 兰德尔 终于找到了
Jonathan Wolverton Randall, finally.
是不列颠军队的重骑兵上尉
Captain of Dragoons in the British Army,
还是你的直系祖先
and your direct ancestor.
也叫黑杰克
Otherwise known as Black Jack.
我听说过克雷尼顿这个地方的故事
I heard stories of a place called Craigh Na Dun.
我已经不是在20世纪了
I was no longer in the 20th century.
弗兰克都经历了些什么
What was Frank going through?
克莱尔
Claire?
也许我被绑架了
Perhaps I was abducted.
也许我死去了
Perhaps I was dead...
或者也许 最糟糕的
Or perhaps, worst of all,
我离开了他 跟随了另一个男人
I had left him for another man.
视频字幕由 SSK字幕组 制作发布
字幕只供学习 请勿做任何商业行为
敬请关注新浪微博@SSK字幕组
翻译：香蕉奶昔 冬可可     校对：金刚妹 佳佳
压制：beloved     时间轴：阿黎     总监：络睿 金刚妹
外乡人第一季  第八集
我是因弗尼斯警局的博伊尔巡警
Inverness police, Constable Boyle speaking,
我能为你效劳吗
how may I help you?
知道了
I see.
是的 女士 我知道了
Yes, ma'am, I see now.
你第一次发现东西丢了 是什么时候
When did you first notice the items were missing?
他回来了
He's back.
我的上帝圣母娘娘啊
Jesus, Mary, and Joseph.
时辰到了
I think today's the day.
就今天吗 先生
Today, sir?
我已经拖太久了
I have let this go on long enough.
就今天 中士
Today, Sergeant.
祝你好运
Good luck.
是的女士 你说的我都听到了
Yes, ma'am, I heard every word you said.
我们会马上派人过去的
I'm gonna send a man over straightaway.
抱歉 兰德尔先生 你知道的
I am sorry, Mr. Randall, you know,
非常非常抱歉
I'm very, very sorry.
我真希望我们能帮上忙
Please believe me when I say
请你相信我的话
I wish there was more that we could do.
当然 你还有自己的事儿
Well, there's your job,
不过也许你能做到
perhaps you could do that.
我知道你肯定很失望
I know this must be disappointing to you.
失望
Disappointing?
真是个有趣的词儿
That's an interesting word.
意思就是期望没有达到
It suggests expectations that were unmet.
不过我对你们部门的期望
My expectations of your department were...
一开始就不高
were low to begin with,
而且我可以确信的是
and I can assure you
这点儿期望你们倒是屡次达到了
that you have met those expectations at every turn.
过去整整六个星期
We have spent the past six weeks
我们搜遍了100平方英里的崎岖地带
searching over 100 square miles of rugged terrain,
实施了175次走访 投入了
conducted 175 interviews, invest-
投入了超过1000个小时的人力时间
Invested over 1,000 man hours.
我知道这些陈词滥调 警官 但你告诉我
I know the litany, Detective, but tell me,
你说进行了这么多努力
what do you have to show for these
想表达什么
for these efforts?
我妻子不见了
My wife has disappeared.
对于她到底发生了什么事情
Do you have any idea at all
你们有没有一点点线索
what might have happened to her?
我们根本没找到尸体
We haven't found a body.
这说明她很可能还活着
Now, that tells me that she's probably still alive.
车里没有血迹 也没有搏斗过的痕迹
No blood in the car, no sign of a struggle,
这说明
now, that tells me that
她很可能不是被强行带走的
she probably wasn't taken against her will.
是啊 你们最喜欢这种解释了
Yeah, your favorite theory.
你说你在她不见的前一个晚上
You personally witnessed a man staring up at her window
看到一个男人盯着她的窗户看
the night before she disappeared.
我从一开始就说
I have said from the very beginning
那个高地人肯定和这件事有关
that the highlander is certainly involved in some way.
他当然有关 你这个傻瓜
Of course he's involved, you fool.
他是她的情夫 他们俩私奔了
He's her lover, and the two of them left together.
我的妻子没有和别的男人在一起
My wife is not with another man.
问你个问题
Ask you a question?
说吧
Of course.
好吧 我的问题是 我不希望
Well, my question, I don't wish to, that is...
我不是说想暗示
I don't mean to imply that you have some
你对男人非常了解
vast knowledge of men,
不过 在这件事上 你了解的确实比我多
but well, you know more than I do in such matters.
你直接说好了
Out with it.
那种感觉
Is it usual,
当我们同枕而眠 当我们肌肤相亲时的感觉
what it is between us when I touch you,
是正常的吗
when you lie with me?
当一个男人和一个女人在一起时 都会有这种感觉吗
Is it always so between a man and a woman?
就像现在这样 这种感觉
It's often something like this.
好吧 其实不正常
No, this isn't usual.
很特别的感觉
It's different.
别动
Don't move.
是你的朋友吗
Friend of yours?
是的 休 休 芒罗
Ay, Hugh, Hugh Munro.
你怎么知道我在这儿
How'd you know I was here?
好吧 你看到杜戈尔和其他人在饮马
Aye, saw Dougal and the others watering the horses?
好的
Aye.
猜到我一定在这上面
Figured I must be up here.
她 克莱尔 我老婆
Her. Claire, my wife.
我们就在前两天结的婚
Married but these two days.
啊 他说他有消息告诉我
Ah, says he's got news,
不过要先和我们喝上两杯
but insists we drink to you first.
我怎么可能拒绝
Canna say I disagree.
好的
Sure.
新婚礼物
Wedding gift.
噢 你真客气
Oh, how kind.
好漂亮
This is beautiful.
是只蜻蜓
It's a dragonfly.
谢谢你
Thank you.
非得搞得这么正式
Gone official, have you?
你戴这玩意儿是不是因为最近没有比赛了
Or are these just for when the game is scarce?
是什么
What are they?
乞丐铭牌
Gaberlunzie tokens.
是英格兰人行乞的许可证
They're licenses to beg, sassenach.
他们只在某个特定的教区才有效
They're good within the borders of a single parish.
特定的教区
Single parish?
我数了数你有一打许可证呀
About a dozen by my count.
是的 好吧
Aye, well,
芒罗很特殊 你要知道
Munro's a special case, you see.
他在海上被土耳其人抓走
He was captured by the Turks at sea.
在阿尔及尔（阿尔及利亚首都）做了好多年奴隶
Spent a good many years as a slave in Algiers.
他就是在那里没了舌头
That's where he lost his tongue.
被割掉了
Cut it out?
他们还往他腿上泼滚烫的油
And poured boiling oil on his legs.
他们就是这样 将一个虔诚的基督徒
It's how they forced captive Christians to convert
变成了一个穆斯林
to Mussulman religion.
你说你有消息告诉我
Said you came wi' news.
谁
Who?
他是怎么知道的
Why would he know?
能信任他吗
Can he be trusted?
他叫什么
What's his name?
哈哈拉卡
Haharack.
哈拉卡
Harack?
哈洛克
Horrock.
哈洛克斯
Horrocks.
这位哈洛克斯想什么时候在哪儿见面
When and where does this Horrocks want to meet?
好的
All right.
谢谢你 真谢谢你 休
Thank you, thank you kindly, Hugh.
有机会可以
There's a chance,
取消对我人头的悬赏
I can get the price lifted from my head.
有一个可以证明我清白的目击证人
There's a witness who can prove my innocence.
他声称
Claims he was there
当我从福特威廉那儿逃走时候 他就在场
during my escape from Fort William,
他看到了杀死中士的那个人
saw who actually killed the sergeant.
不过我不确定能否相信他
But I'm not sure I can trust him.
那个叫哈洛克斯的吗
Is this Horrocks?
是的 是个英格兰逃兵
Aye, a redcoat deserter.
不过终于能有机会
But if there's a chance I can finally go home
我可以眷携佳人
with my bride,
克莱尔 弗雷泽一起回归故里
Claire Fraser, Lady of Lallybroch...
有没有沿芬德霍恩河找过
What about the Findhorn River?
你跟他们提过吗
Did you tell them?
他们 额 他们不感兴趣
They, uh, they weren't interested.
这是推理啊 很好的推理
It's a theory, a good one.
她离开了克雷尼顿
She leaves Craigh Na Dun,
迷了路 又回头了
gets lost, turns back,
想沿着芬德霍恩河回来
tries to follow the Findhorn River,
脚下一滑 然后被河水冲走
takes a misstep, and then is swept away by the current,
一直被冲到达纳韦森林
all the way down to the Darnaway Forest.
达纳韦森林离找到车子的地方有20英里
Darnaway Forest is 20 miles from where the car was found.
啊 河水湍急 那晚水流特别快
Ah, the river is fast, and it was swift that night.
都能带着她来回一趟了
She could've been carried twice that far.
关于这篇区域 这些地图画得比较含糊
These maps of the area, they're poor.
也许在河流的某个弯曲处
Looks as though there are bends in the river here
她被冲到了岸上
where she might have made it to shore,
然后在这山脊中找了个地方栖身 可能
and then found shelter along this ridge, maybe,
可能找了个山洞
maybe in a cave.
于是她又累又迷茫
So she's tired, she's lost,
不知去向何处
she doesn't know where to turn.
所以她在洞里屈身躺下 保持温暖
So she hunkers down in this cave to keep warm,
靠鱼和青蛙为食 等待救援
and lives on fish and frogs while waiting to be found.
靠鱼和青蛙活了七个星期
Fish and frogs for seven weeks?
她受过军队的生存训练
She relied on her army survival training.
她是个坚强的女人 她也很聪明 她
She's a strong woman. She's smart. She's-
这推理只是瞎找的救命稻草而已
We're grasping at straws.
先生们
Gentlemen...
- 茶点准备好了 - 还有小饼干
- Tea is served. - And biscuits.
噢 谢谢你 罗杰
Oh, thank you, Roger.
请问我能吃一块小饼干吗
May I have a biscuit, please?
你要吃第二块小饼干吗 好吧
You mean another biscuit? Aye.
你是不是吃了我所有的小饼干啊 罗杰 威克菲尔德
Have you been eating all my biscuits, Roger Wakefield?
快上楼去 准备睡觉觉
Now, go upstairs, and get ready for bed.
我马上就上来给你念故事听
I'll be up in a minute to read you a story.
我想我需要更有力的线索
I think I need something a little stronger.
我陪你一起去找吧
Care for some company?
不用了 谢谢 别等我了
No, thank you. Don't wait up.
你要点些什么
What can I get you?
什么都不需要
Nothing.
晚安 兰德尔先生
Evening, Mr. Randall.
你可以叫我莎莉 不过不是我的真名
You can call me Sally, but that's not my real name.
我可以为你效劳么 莎莉
What can I do for you, Sally?
是我可以为你效劳么
It's what I can do for you.
我知道他在哪儿
I ken where he is.
哪里
Where?
不远
Close.
我带你去
I'll take you to him.
不是现在
Not now.
周围耳目众多
There's too many eyes and ears in here.
来德拉蒙德巷找我
Meet me on Drummond Lane,
十二点半的时候 你从鞋匠的店经过
Just past the cobbler shop at half past 12:00.
你一个人来 带好报酬
Come alone and bring the reward.
他和她在一起吗
Is he with her?
我的妻子
My wife?
我不知道
I don't know.
我能做的只是把你带到他那儿去
All I can do is take you to where he is.
之后就不关我的事了
After that, it's your concern.
记住 十二点半
Remember, half past 12:00.
再来一杯
Another.
于是河马带着建筑师
And so the waterhorse carries the builder
走向水中
straight into the water,
并且沉到很深的水底
and down through the depths
带他来到了自己冰冷还带着鱼腥味的小屋
to his own cold, fishy home,
然后他告诉建房子的人 如果他想要自由
then he tells the builder if he would be free,
必须先建一座漂亮的房子
he must build a fine house,
还要有一个烟囱
and a muckle chimney as well,
这样河马的妻子就能用火暖手
so that the waterhorse's wife could warm her hands
还可以炸鱼
by the fire and fry her fish.
没有别的选择 建楼的人只好照着他的话做
And the builder, having little choice, did as he was bid,
因为河马的妻子在她的新家里
because the waterhorse's wife was sad,
感到非常难过 寒冷和饥饿
and cold, and hungry in her new home beneath the waves.
我们回到理士的时候刚好是圣诞季节
Be yuletide by the time we get back to Leoch.
圣诞节
Christmas...
你们肯定不会在火炉边挂长袜
I don't suppose you hang stockings by the fire.
是为了把它们烤干吗
To dry them off, you mean?
当我没说
Never mind.
后来河马的妻子感到很温暖
And the waterhorse's wife was warm then,
也很开心 家里存满了她为晚饭所准备的烤鱼
and happy, and full of the fish she fried for her supper,
但是当那个人来到
but when the man came down to the...
怎么了
What's the matter?
那些马 它们很躁动
The horses, they're restless.
有人在附近
Someone's near.
现在先别动 我们都感觉到了
Now, don't move. We all know.
消失在了阴暗的水中
...disappearing into the murky waters below.
于是加夫湖东部的水域
And the waters of the east end
再也没有结冰过
of Loch Garve never freeze over,
因为从河马家烟囱传来的热气把冰给融化了
because the heat from the waterhorse's chimney melts the ice.
看见那棵倒下的树了吗
See that fallen tree?
等会你就过去 待在那别动
When I say, go to it and don't move.
拿上这个
Take this.
住在水里的河马只有鱼一样的牙齿
The waterhorse beneath the waves has but fish's teeth
只能吃到蜗牛和水草
and feeds on snails and water weeds
和其他一些湿冷的东西
and cold, wet things.
他的血液和水一样冰冷
His blood runs cold as water
不再需要火焰
and has no need of fire.
快走 注意马车
Go! Mind the wagon!
给我下来
Get off!
他们想要粮食和马匹
They're going for the grain and the horses.
别过来
Stay back.
回来啊
Come on, ye!
给我回来
Come on!
克莱尔
Claire!
我没事
I'm all right.
我很好
那些人是谁
Who were those men?
格兰特人
The Grants.
他们有抢走什么东西吗
Did they take anything?
一匹马 三袋粮食
A horse, three bags of grain,
钱没被偷
but none of the money.
- 一匹马 - 可能更糟
- A horse? - Could've been worse.
- 你还好吧 威利 - 是的
- Are you all right, Willie? - Aye.
看到他们逃跑的速度了吗
Did you see that shot?
简直一溜烟儿呀
It was at 20 paces if it was one.
兰德尔先生
Mr. Randall,
我还以为你不会出现了
I was starting to think you weren't gonna show.
我想我还没迟到
I believe I'm on time.
我只是以为你会早到
I just thought you might be early.
这里
Here.
哪里
Where?
把钱交出来
Give us the reward.
住手
Stop!
求你了 快住手
Stop, please!
他会死掉的
You're gonna kill him!
不要
No! No! No!
这里根本就没有高地人
There is no highlander is there?
是不是
Is there?
没有
No, no!
在这个现代社会
It's fashionable in this modern age
大家都不再理会善恶之分
to dismiss the idea of good and evil,
但邪恶还是会存在
but there is evil,
并且它总是打好人的主意
and it finds purchase in good men
让罪人纵享狂热带来的快感
by giving sin the sweet taste of ecstasy.
纳粹党喝下毒药
The Nazis drank from that poisoned cup,
还以为他们喝的只是
thinking all the while they were slaking
美味可口的红酒
their thirst with the sweetest wine.
你的意思是
Are you suggesting that I have
我也在喝同样的酒吗
been drinking from the same cup?
邪恶之酒只有一杯
Evil has but one cup.
他们一般会慢慢品尝
They drank long and deep.
你只不过刚尝一口
Yours was but a sip.
不要再继续尝试了
Make it your last.
不要再让黑暗指引着你
Turn away from the darkness that beckons you,
要回头走向光明
and go back into the light.
你是说让我离开因弗尼斯
You mean leave Inverness.
是的
Aye.
回到牛津去
Go back to Oxford.
重新开始你的生活
You start your life over.
那克莱尔呢
And what of Caire?
别管她了 就像她不管你一样
Let her go, just as she has let you go.
所以你认为她是自愿
So you believe that she left with the Highlander
跟着高地人离开的
of her own volition?
你有没有读过福尔摩斯这本书 弗兰克
Have you ever read Sherlock Holmes, Frank?
写得非常好
Marvelous books.
里面有提到一个观点
One point he makes,
当你排除掉所有不可能的情况
when you eliminate the impossible,
剩下的即使再不可能
whatever remains, however improbable,
也只能是真相
must be the truth.
我不知道
I don't know.
就从我手里不见了
It just slipped out of my hand.
找到了
Found it.
好家伙
Good man.
对我来说这又长又重
It's too long and heavy for me.
女人都这么跟我说的
Lasses say that to me all the time.
你给她把刀
You gave her a knife
却不告诉她怎么用
and you didn't show her how to use it.
该找个人教教这位女士
Someone should teach this lady how to
如何保护自己不受攻击
defend herself against assailants.
没错 安格斯 你刀使得很好
Aye, Angus, you're a good man with a blade.
谢谢你的好意 不过我想我不会有事的
Uh, thank you all the same, but I think I'll be fine.
这个世界上所有人 不管男女
Every man and woman in the world needs to know
都必须学会如何保护自己 英格兰女士
how to defend themselves, Sassenach,
尤其是那些嫁给了苏格兰人的女人
Especially those married to a Fraser.
我已经越来越意识到这一点了
I become more aware of that every day.
- 女人得有一个斯金度 - 没错
- Lass needs a sgian dubh. - Aye.
什么东西
A what?
斯金度 隐蔽刀
Sgian dubh, hidden dagger.
有些人把它们藏在袜子里
Some people hide them in their socks,
不过我把它放在更私人的地方
but I- keep mine in a rather more private place.
现在 谁想要上一课
Now then, who needs a lesson?
大部分情况都是往上刺
Mostly, you want to use the underhand.
当你快要倒在某人身上
Overhand is only good if you're coming down
并且对方的力气非常大的时候
on someone else with a considerable force
往下刺才会比较好
from above ye.
我还是觉得对女人来说毒药才是最好的武器
I still say the only good weapon for a woman is poison.
也许吧 但打起来的时候这招可不好使
Perhaps, but it has certain deficiencies in combat.
知道了
All right.
那我该朝哪刺下去
So where do I aim my sgian dubh?
如果你们是面对面的话
If you're killing face to face,
这里
here.
用最大的力气
Aim straight up, and then,
朝着心脏笔直地刺下去
as hard as you can into the heart.
不 要避免刺到胸骨
Uhoh, avoid the breast bone.
如果你把刀刺进这个柔软的部位的话
You get your knife stuck in that soft part on the top,
你的小刀就再也派不上用场了
you'll be without a knife.
那么 是这里
So... right there?
现在先别急着杀他 小姐
Dinnae kill him yet, mistress.
等上完课先
Wait 'til the lesson's over.
威利 过来帮个忙
Willie, give us a hand.
转过去 我来演示一下如何从背后攻击
Turn around, so I can show how to kill from behind.
瞄准背部的这个地方
Now, this is the spot in the back.
两边都行
Either side will do.
现在你知道所有的肋骨在哪了
Now, you see where all the ribs and such?
当你刺向背部的时候
Very difficult to hit anything vital
很难刺中要害
when you stab in the back.
刀会从肋骨间穿过
Slip the knife between the ribs, huh?
这很重要
That's one thing.
比你想象的要难得多
A lot harder to do than ye might think.
拿着 这里
Here, here.
在最后一根肋骨的下面
Just under the last rib,
从下面往上
you stab upward...
刺入肾脏
and into the kidney.
直直地
Straight up.
敌人就跟快石头一样倒下去了
They'll drop like a stone.
好吧
All right.
直直地
Straight up...
刺进去
and in.
看 我学会了
See, got it.
他们会不会来找我们
Won't they come looking for us?
我跟杜戈尔说过了
I told Dougal
我们还要再跟你找些草药
we need to find some more of your wee herbs.
这是我出的主意 不是吗
This is my idea, is it?
他相信你了吗
And did he believe you?
那还用说
Never a chance.
完全无法停止对你的渴望
Does it ever stop, the wanting you?
现在我知道为什么教堂会把这称为圣礼了
Now I know why the church calls it a sacrament.
为什么
Why?
当我进入你体内的时候 感觉自己就像上帝一样
Because I feel like god himself when I'm inside ye.
什么
What?
是不是听起来很愚蠢
Is that a foolish thing to say?
你在嘲笑我
You're laughing at me.
没错 的确是的
Yes, I most certainly am.
那我可要给你好看
And you'll get what you deserve.
起来 你这个发情的杂种
Get up, you rutting bastard.
你应该让他先弄完的
You might ha' let him finish first, 'arry.
中途停下来 对男人的身子可不好
Stoppin' in the middle, now that's bad for a man's 'ealth.
又不是我的身子
Oh, his 'ealth's no concern of mine.
反正等会他也会没命的
It won't be any concern of his for much longer.
把他杀了 别管他了
Well, kill him, and be done with it then,
现在我也来尝尝甜头
'cause I've a mind to take a piece o' that.
不
No...
我还会让你先看一阵
think I'll let 'im watch first.
喜欢吗 苏格兰杂种
You like that, you Scottish whoreson?
看好了 小禽兽
Take a good look, laddiebuck,
给我看仔细了
see how it's done,
等会我会让这贱人
'cause I'll have your slut moaning for more
喊得更淫荡
before the hour is done.
不要
No!
我已经几周没说过话
I have held my tongue for weeks now,
我再也不会当哑巴了
and I'll be silent no longer.
你不能告诉他你的幻想
You cannot tell him this fantasy of yours.
我知道的很清楚 我不会装傻子的
I know what I know, and I won't pretend that I don't.
你所知道的
What you know is
都是一派胡言
a bunch of dribbledrabble and nonsense,
我不会把它当作真相的
and I will not have it paraded about as fact.
他有权知道这些 并且自己决定
He has a right to hear it and make up his own mind.
你不能给这个可怜的人再带来虚幻的希望
You cannot hold up false hope to the poor man,
他好不容易终于接受她老婆的事实
just as he's finally accepting that his wife...
这是一栋老房子
It's an old house.
好吧 那个
All right, well...
你是不是想跟我说什么 格雷厄姆夫人
Is there something you wish to tell me, Mrs. Graham?
是的
There is.
即使这违背了我的立场
Even if it should cost me my position,
但我觉得我必须把真相告诉你
I feel I must tell you the truth.
- 真相 - 至少是我知道的那部分真相
- The truth - The truth as I know it.
你妻子的事情 还有另外一种可能
There is an other explanation for what happened to your wife.
这是个古老的故事
The stories are old.
有人说和那些石头一样古老
Some say as old as the stones themselves,
在民谣和民歌里
passed down from generation to generation
代代相传
through ballads and songs.
我第一次是从我祖母那儿听来的
I first heard them from my grandmother,
她也是从她祖母那儿听来的
and she from hers.
那首民歌 唱的是
The songs tell stories about people who...
人们穿越石头的故事
travel through the stones.
穿越石头
Travel through stone?
我不太理解你的意思
I'm not sure I take your meaning.
倒不是说真的穿过石头本身
Not literally through the stone itself.
就是
You see...
克雷尼顿的石头圆圈
the circle at Craigh Na Dun marks a...
标志着地球上的一个地方
a place on the earth
在那个地方 自然的力量汇聚在一起
where the powers of nature come together.
简直是迷信和胡话
Superstition and twiddletwaddle.
你接着说
Go on.
石头采集天地之力
The stones gather the powers,
聚焦到一点 就像凸透镜一样 知道吗
and give it focus, like a glass, ye ken?
对特定的人
And for certain people,
在特定的日子
on certain days,
石头之力会使其穿透时间的面纱
it allows them to pierce the veil of time.
兰德尔先生 你知道你妻子
Mr. Randall, you know your wife
不见的那天上了山
went up that hill the day she vanished.
我相信她并没有从山上下来
I believe she didn't come back down that hill,
至少不是在1945年从山上下来的
at least not in 1945.
我相信她穿越到了
I believe that she traveled to
另外的时代里
some other time.
她会去哪里 会去哪个时代呢
Where or... when would that be?
我不知道
I don't know.
每个穿越者都不一样
Every traveler is different.
他们必须走自己的路
They must make their own journey
经历自己的旅程
on their own path,
不过古老的民歌里确实有说
but the songs do say
穿越者们 通常又会回到这个时代来
that the travelers often return.
我知道了
I see.
我今天下午就回牛津
I shall leave for Oxford this afternoon.
你听到我说的了吗
Did ye no hear me?
- 格雷厄姆夫人 - 他们通常会回来的
- Mrs. Graham. - They often return.
我听到你说的了
I did hear you.
我只是不相信你所说的
I simply do not share your beliefs.
原谅我
Forgive me.
对不起
Sorry.
真的对不起
I'm so sorry.
没事儿
It's all right.
我们没事儿了
We're all right.
都是我的错
My fault.
把你带来这里 没给你保暖
To bring you here without taking proper heat,
让你
and to let you be...
还无力去阻止
to not stop him.
没事儿
It's all right.
你的手好冷
And here, you're so cold mo nighean donn.
冷得像冰一样
Your hands are like ice.
杰米
Jamie!
- 吓坏了 - 你还好吗
- It's shock. - Are you all right?
我们听到了枪响
We heard a shot.
我吓坏了
I'm going into shock.
杰米
Jamie.
带着别动
Stay.
我吓坏了
I'm going into shock.
没事儿的
It's all right.
我脑海里万千思绪闪跃而过
My mind jumped and danced from thought to thought,
就像石头打水漂一样不断跳跃
like a stone skipping across a pond.
我父母 我看着死去的人
My parents, men I'd seen die,
兰姆叔叔的烟味儿
the smell of uncle Lamb's cigarettes.
埃罗尔 弗林 荡着秋千
Errol Flynn swinging on a rope,
握着匕首刺穿肾脏的感觉
the feeling of my dagger tip puncturing the kidney.
我知道他很担心我
I knew he was worried about me,
知道他想谈刚才发生的事
knew he wanted to talk about what had happened,
可是我知道 如果我再次谈起
but I knew if I did,
如果我开始想我脆弱屈服
if I started giving rein to my feelings,
所有痛苦回忆都会向我扑面而来
things would pour out of me
那些我想永远赶走的痛苦回忆
that I wanted to keep locked away forever.
只是吓坏了
It's shock.
没事儿的
It's all right.
标志在这儿
There's letters.
从山脊那边过来的 没有骑马
The tracks lead back over the ridge, no horses.
很好
Good.
你说的哈洛克斯
Your man Horrocks.
芒罗说他就是像这两个人一样的逃兵
Munro said he's a deserter like these.
休 芒罗是个好人
Hugh Munro's a good man.
这我不否认
I won't deny it,
但违背对国王和国家的誓言的人
but this is what becomes of a man
就是这副样子
who breaks his oath to king and country.
如果你现在一个人去见哈洛克斯
Now, you go and see Horrocks alone,
更像是走向圈套
you'll be walking into a trap, maist like.
他说得对 杰米
He's right, Jamie.
你非去见他不可 我理解
You have to meet him, I understand that,
但要我说的话 我们带着武器和你一起去
but I say we all go with you with our swords in our hands.
不然的话 你索性就别去
Otherwise, you don't go at all.
好吧
Aye.
来
Come on.
我记不得是怎么上的马
I don't remember getting on my horse.
不知道怎么一路骑过去的 甚至骑了多久都不记得了
I don't remember riding away, or even how long we rode.
我能回忆起的 只有我人生中那些关键的时刻
All I can recall of that pivotal moment in my life
只有愤怒的感觉 我也不知道为什么
was that I was angry, and I didn't know why.
为什么停下
Why are we stopping?
你和韦利要留在这里
You'll have to stay here with Willie.
什么
What?
杜格尔说得对
Dougal was right.
这可能是哈洛克斯的圈套
Now, this man Horrocks may be setting a trap.
我不会再让你冒险了
I'll no risk you again.
有韦利在这保护你 会安全得多
You'll be safer here with Willie to look out for ye.
我不想听这些
I don't need an explanation.
你带上韦利吧
You can take Willie with you.
我能照顾好自己
I can look after myself.
我觉得之前我已经证明过了
I think I've proven that earlier.
你不需要再证明一次
You needn't prove it again.
如果有英格兰士兵
If there are redcoats about,
他们最可能从南面过来
they'll likely come from the south.
- 我会十分小心的 - 好吧
- I'll keep an eye out. - Aye.
你就在这里
You stay here.
我会回来的 我保证
I'll be back, I promise.
你不应该做没有把握的保证
You shouldn't make promises you can't keep.
这一次我可以保证 克莱尔
This one I will keep, Claire.
现在你答应我 你会待着不动
Now, you promise me you'll stay put.
- 杰米 - 来了
- Jamie. - Coming!
答应我 克莱尔
Promise me, Claire.
发誓我回来的时候 你还会在这里
Swear you'll be here when I get back.
好吧 我保证
Fine, I promise.
好
Good.
在那个时刻
In that moment,
我痛苦的原因非常清晰了
the reason for my bitterness became clear to me.
我不是在生杰米的气 也不是在恨那两个英格兰逃兵
I wasn't angry at Jamie or the redcoat deserters.
我是在生我自己的气
I was angry at myself
因为我全然忘记了我的计划
for forgetting about my plan to make
全然忘记了要回到克雷尼顿的石头那儿去
my way back to the stones at Craigh Na Dun,
回到我自己的时代
my plan to return to my own time,
回到丈夫弗兰克的身边
to my husband, Frank.
柏林的美军总部宣布
U.S. Army headquarters in Berlin announced
乔治巴顿二世将军 在今天过世
the death of General George S. Patton, Jr. Earlier today
死于12天前的车祸中所受的重伤
from injuries he sustained in a car accident 12 days ago.
凯迪拉克75型号专车
...Cadillac model 75 staff car,
把将军送往
transporting the general...
同车的有一等兵霍雷斯 伍德林
as well as private first class Horace L. Woodring
车子在西班牙境外与一辆卡车相撞
collided with a truck just outside of Spain.
作为一个颇具争议的人物 巴顿将军经历了
A controversial figure, General Patton's career
第一次和第二次世界大战
spanned both the first and second world wars,
现任美国第三军的指挥官
most recently as commander of the U.S. Third Army.
夫人
Mistress?
Mistress!
怎么了
What?
我去解决一下个人问题
If you need me,
你有需要就请叫我
I'll just be taking care of some personal business.
去50码开外的下风口
Go at least 50 yards away and downwind.
是
Aye.
我努力不去想那天草原上发生的事
I tried to avoid thinking about the incident in the meadow,
可我的脑海里不断回闪
but my mind kept returning to it,
一遍又一遍
again, and again,
就像去碰一个碰不得的溃烂伤口
picking at a festering sore best left untouched.
突然 它就出现了
And suddenly, there it was...
克雷尼顿
Craigh Na Dun.
我的心里充满了迷茫和疑惑
My mind had been so clouded and confused,
我已经认不出来时的路了
I didn't recognize the road when we rode in.
没有弄错
There was no mistaking it.
我又回来了
I was back
回到了这一切开始的地方
to the place where it had all begun.
发生了太多事 发生了太多改变
So much had happened. So much had changed.
上次我在这里 我还是克莱尔兰德尔
Last I was here, I was Claire Randall,
然后成了克莱尔毕彻姆
then Claire Beauchamp,
之后又成了克莱尔弗雷泽
then Claire Fraser.
问题是 我到底想成为谁
The question was... who did I want to be?
克莱尔
Claire.
Claire!
你在哪里 克莱尔
Where are you, Claire?
弗兰克
Frank!
克莱尔
Claire!
弗兰克
Frank,
等着我
wait for me,
弗兰克
Frank!
克莱尔
Claire.
弗兰克
Frank!
不
No!
弗兰克
Frank!
克莱尔
Claire.
不用问我也知道我们会去哪里
I knew where we were going without having to ask:
福特 威廉
Fort William.
四年前
The site of Jamie's incarceration
杰米遭到监禁和鞭笞的地方
and flogging four years ago,
如今 仍然是某人的私人领地
and now, still the province of a man
而且很不幸地 他了解发生过的一切
I unfortunately knew all too well.（I应该是and）
不过他不知道我已经被抓了
He would have no advance notice of my capture.
所以没时间安排审讯
No time to plan his interrogation.
而我 在颠簸的马车后面
I, on the other hand, had the entire jolting journey
有一路的时间来思考怎么办
in the back of the wagon to think.
这是我的优势
It was my one advantage.
我希望时间还够
I prayed it would be enough.
要祝贺你新婚快乐
Felicitations and congratulations on your recent marriage.
虽然我并不特别在意
Though I don't particularly care
你把自己当英格兰人还是苏格兰人
whether you consider yourself an Englishwoman or a Scot...
而且很显然 两者都不是
and apparently, neither do you.
你还戴着你原来的婚戒
You still wear your old wedding ring?
情感的寄托而已
Sentimental attachment.
我很怀疑你心中还有没有情感
I doubt you have a sentimental bone in your body.
不过更有意思的问题是
But the more interesting question is
为什么杜戈尔 麦肯齐会如此珍视你
why would Dougal MacKenzie consider you of such value,
竟收留你把你当自己人
that he would rather adopt you as one of his own
却不容许我质疑你
than allow me to question you?
我根本不知道你在说些什么
I am sure I have no idea what you're talking about.
真的吗
Really?
敬国王
The king.
我很高兴地听到 你还把国王当做君主
I'm glad to hear that you still consider him your sovereign.
我们麦肯齐家族忠诚不渝
We MacKenzies are all loyal subjects.
这是我整一星期以来
That is the single most amusing thing
听到的唯一一件好笑的事情
I've heard all week.
我可以以为鞭笞那些无辜的犯人
So I take it you haven't been amusing yourself
并没能逗乐你
by flogging some innocent prisoners then?
逗乐我
Amusing myself?
说起来真是怪怪的
What an odd thing to say.
从我们过去的会面来看 你是知道的
As you know from our previous meeting,
我确确实实把惩罚看作是很严肃的事
I consider flogging a very serious matter indeed.
夫人
Madam,
你要了解你现在的处境
you need to understand your position.
此时此刻 我们第三次交锋
In this hour, our third encounter,
我十分希望即使采取任何必要手段
I fully intend by any means necessary
揭开你的本性
to discover both your true nature
还有你掩藏的秘密
and the secrets that you hold.
也许你该问问桑德林罕姆公爵
Perhaps you should ask the Duke of Sandringham.
哦 我的天呀
Oh, dear me,
我希望不会留下污迹
I do hope that won't stain.
虽然是棋行险招
A dangerous gambit to be sure,
但他的反应告诉我 弗兰克和教士的
but his reaction told me that Frank and the Reverend
推测是正确的
were right in their speculation.
我怀疑你的祖先有一个庇护人
I suspect your ancestor had a patron,
一个非凡强大的人
a prominent and powerful man who could protect him
来庇护他 不受来自他上级的责难
from the censure of his superiors.
有可能是那个时代非常高层的人
Possibly, but it would have to have been someone very high up
才能施加如此巨大的影响
in the hierarchy of the day to exert that kind of influence.
桑德林罕姆公爵
The Duke of Sandringham?
黑杰克能够在高地
Black Jack was able to commit his various crimes
犯下如此残酷的罪行
in the highlands
就是因为他被一个位高权重的人所庇护着
because he was being protected by a powerful man,
这种庇护的代价
and the cost of such protection
通常就是沉默和忠诚
was always silence and fidelity.
关于公爵你都知道些什么
What do you know of the Duke?
真的吗 上尉 你非得这么迟钝不可吗
Really, captain, must you be so obtuse?
到现在还不清楚吗
Is it not clear by now
你和我都在一个伟大而
that you and I are both in the employ
权重的人的庇护之下吗
of the same great and powerful man?
不可能的
That is impossible.
他会跟我说的
He would've told me.
因为他会把所有秘密都告诉你吗
Because he tells you all his secrets?
你对他来说一定是以为非常特别的军官
You must be a very special officer indeed.
我只要派个信使去桑德林罕姆问问他就可以了
I will simply send a message to Sandringham asking him.
好主意
Excellent idea.
我敢肯定 他看到你如此敏锐地
I'm sure he'll be most pleased at your skill and acumen
察觉到我的真实身份的时候 一定会很开心的
at uncovering my identity,
或者
or...
公爵并不会赞赏你
perhaps your disruption of the Duke's
去打搅他精心布下的局
carefully laid plans will not be rewarded.
也许他会不高兴
Perhaps he will be displeased,
从而考虑结束你们之间的特殊关系
and take measures to terminate your special relationship,
收回对你惯有的庇护
withdraw the protection to which you've become accustomed,
这样好让你的上级军官
and thus leave you at the mercy
还有当地的土豪 来好好疼爱你
of your superior officers and local authorities.
当然 最明智的行为
No, the wisest course of action
就是让我继续我的任务
would be to allow me to continue my mission
我不会向公爵提到
and give the Duke no indication of how close you came
你差点就破坏了他为了王国所付出的心血
to disrupting his efforts on behalf of the king.
当然你是说 他的 呃 他夫人的心血
You mean, of course, his, uh, his wife's efforts.
他夫人
His wife?
公爵夫人 你见过她了吗
The duchess. You've met her?
哦 我一直没能有那个荣幸
Oh, I've never had the pleasure.
真的吗
Really?
公爵的代理人 就是公爵夫人的代理人
An agent of the Duke is an agent of the duchess.
当然 我们一直有联系
Well, we have been in communication.
用书信联系
Communication by letter?
- 信使 是的 - 和公爵夫人
- By messenger, yes. - With the duchess?
我们说的就是她 不是吗
That's who we're talking about, isn't it?
是的
Yes.
正是
That is, uh...
我们说的正是她
that is who we're talking about.
可是 当然 嗯
But, of course, um...
公爵从来没有结过婚
the duke has never been married.
下士
Corporal.
对不起 夫人
I'm sorry, madam.
一位绅士怎么会在桌子里放绳索
What kind of gentleman keeps a rope at his desk?
一位时刻准备着的绅士 夫人
A prepared one, madam.
你可以走了 霍金斯
You can go, Hawkins.
还有 下士
And corporal,
别回来 不管你听到什么
don't come back, no matter what you hear.
- 去吧 - 是
- Go. - Sir.
救命 来人啊
Help, somebody!
救救我
Help me!
现在
Now...
我觉得我们应该从你的名字开始 嗯
I think we should begin with your name, hmm?
你的真实姓名
Your real name.
然后
Then...
你可以告诉我你知道的所有事情
you can tell me everything that you know about...
杜戈尔 麦肯齐
Dougal MacKenzie...
他的兄弟 科勒姆
his brother Colum...
那个 额
the, uh...
詹姆斯党人叛乱
the Jacobite rebellion...
还有 最后
and finally,
桑德林罕姆公爵
the Duke of Sandringham.
你会后悔的
You are going to regret this.
我很怀疑
I doubt it.
这是啥
What have we here?
天啊天啊
My, my.
这位女士还有利爪呢
The lady has claws.
锋利吗
Are they sharp?
嗯 锋利吗
Hmm, are they?
把手从我妻子身上拿开 我先谢谢您
I'll thank ye to take your hands off my wife.
嘿 天哪
Good god.